To ultimately achieve happiness
然后来到达一个幸福的目的
What do I mean by that
这是什么意思呢
Check out the post I shared on my social media yesterday
看我昨天发了一条朋友圈
Let me tell you,
我就说呀
I often watch videos from other UPloaders
经常我去看其他up主的视频
Then leave a comment and give a like
然后给人家留言评论点赞啊
practically groveling like a dog,
像一条狗一样舔别人
but most of the time, these people don't return the favor by following me back.
但很多的时候呢这些人不会回粉
So, I usually unfollow them after a few days.
所以呢我就过几天就取关了
Well, this is what I face with most UPloaders.
哎这我面对大部分up主啊
This applies to those with more followers or fewer followers than me.
这不管是粉丝数量比我多的还是比我低的
My habit is being a follower.
我的习惯就是粉丝啊
It doesn't matter.
无所谓啊
Generally speaking,
一般来讲的话
You're the captain,
你是舰长
What kind of premium Power Up member are you?
你是什么高级充电会员
What are you?
你是什么
Leave me a comment so we can interact more and maybe get on the engagement leaderboard,
跟我留留言比较互动的排名榜号
I always respond to my followers before the video.
看前我都会回粉啊
Everyone can see that I have a lot of followers on my Bilibili account.
大家看我的B站关注数量特别多啊
Posting on social media works the same way.
发朋友圈也是一样
I post on my Moments too.
我发朋友圈也是
It's the same group of followers who give me likes every day.
就是天天给我点赞的是同一批粉丝
That makes me really happy.
然后我特别的高兴啊
but the number of likes
但是点赞的数量
and the number of comments are just too many.
留言的数量太多了
Sometimes I can't even keep up.
有时候一回都来不及
But if someone doesn't usually give me likes Suddenly gave me a like I'll be especially thrilled. Over time you'll notice people's behavior patterns enter a predictable state which is why we often talk about pure love warriors and idealists
但是如果谁平时不给我点赞 突然给我点赞了 我就会特别高兴 久而久之 你会发现人的这个行为模式呢 进入一种可预判的状态 所以我们常说纯爱战士理想主义者
because I used to be a pure love warrior and an idealist myself
因为我以前就是一个纯爱战士加理想主义者
so when it comes to the judgment of good and evil in this world
所以我对这世间的一些善恶善恶的
how I make these judgments of good and evil
这个怎么善恶的这种判断的来讲的话
is based on other people's reactions
我是根据别人的反应来的
but let's say if your actions
但是但是咱们说如果你的行动
Behaviors are often judged by others' reactions.
行为都是通过别人的反应来讲的话
Your actions become predictable.
你的行为就好预判
This makes you more susceptible to manipulation.
你就容易被人PUA
Why is that?
为什么呢
Because others only need to give you intermittent rewards.
因为别人只需要间歇性的给你奖励就可以了
And the intervals between these rewards gradually increase.
而且他这个间隔呢逐渐的加大
This is why, for example, your significant other might act in a certain way.
这就是为什么有时候比如说你的男女朋友
Their mood swings can be unpredictable.
她她情绪不稳定
Sometimes they can be really low and erratic.
疯逼特别low的一个人
But you just like him
但是你就是喜欢他
It's like being in a state of torment
就是一种被折磨的状态
What they call the gaslighting effect, right
所谓的煤气灯效应是吧
He plays you and manipulates you
被他PV都被他套路了
That's how it is
就是这样
His moods keep shifting
就是他的情绪不停的转换
Sometimes he's nice to you
期间呢就是一会儿跟你好
And other times he's not
一会儿对你不好啊
You gradually start to look forward to the next time he's nice to you But if your feedback mechanism for behavior changes, what's called random toxic responses, it leads to this, you have to engage in intense self-deception,
你就会逐渐的期待他下一次对你好的一个过程 但是呢如果你这人的行为反馈机制变了啊 所谓的随机以毒乱回 就达到这样 就是你要进行大强度的欺骗自己
no matter what,
无论怎么样
whether the other person hits you or insults you,
对方无论是打你还是骂你
or is kind to you,
还是对你好
you feel that they must love you,
你都觉得对方一定爱我
at this point, you've entered a state where
这个时候你就进入了一种
A state of self-hypnosis
自我催眠的一种状态啊
No matter if others hit you or scold you
别人无论是打你骂你
You think all these people are NPCs, huh?
你都觉得啊这些人都是NPC啊
created for me to complete quests and earn rewards
这些人都是为我拿任务奖励而造的
so I only need to focus on
所以我一切东西我只需要啊
I am a legend
我就是一个传奇
I am a chosen one
我就是一个天选之子
Once you have this confidence
你有这种自信了
it can also become a real effect
他也就可以变成一种真实的作用了
For example, when we talk about Comrade Trump
比如说我们说特朗普同志啊
Comrade Trump was born on June 14th
特朗普同志6月14号出生哦
I share the same birthday with many famous historical figures
我跟好多历史联盟名人都是一天出生的
Why do I say I share the same birthday with Trump
为什么说我跟特朗普也是一天出生
Because of the International Date Line on planet Earth
因为地七地球这个日期变更线
Their June 14th is our June 15th
他们的6月14就是我们的6月15
So, in a mysterious way
所以特朗普冥冥之中
Trump still shares his birthday with many people
还是跟很多人都是同一天生日啊
But we, who share the same birthday on this day These people, being Geminis, are pretty unreliable. They're quite unreliable. But one trait of Geminis is that they don't easily fall into depression. They might cause others to feel depressed, but they don't get depressed themselves.
但是我们这一天同一天过生日的人 这帮人双子座呢就是有多不靠谱 有多不靠谱 但是双子座的一个特点就是不太容易抑郁啊 会导致他人抑郁 但不会自己抑郁
We have this high-intensity way of deceiving both ourselves and others.
我们就是一种高强度的欺骗自己跟欺骗
the world around us.
这个世界
Actually, deceiving others isn't that hard,
其实欺骗别人来讲难度不大
because, at the end of the day, one's identity in society is self-imposed.
因为你说白了人在外身份是自己给的
Whether you embellish it
无论你通过美化也好
or belittle it
通过贬低也好
no matter what
无论是怎么样
if you don't express your true feelings
只要你表露出不是你的真心
it's essentially a form of performance
其实本身都是一种表演行为
However, many people don't understand the importance of self-love
但是我们说很多人并不明白自爱的重要性
self-respect, self-love, and self-strengthening
自尊自爱自强
much of the time
很多的时候
you can't make everyone like you
你是没有办法达到让所有人喜欢你的
So, all your life's efforts are to legitimize yourself.
所以你一生努力必也正名乎的
In the end, the result is that you've exhausted your energy.
最后的结果就是你耗尽了精力
To make all those people in the world who you think are important
让这世界上所有你觉得很重要的人
care about you.
让他们关心你
But in reality, these people won't care about you.
但是实际上这些人不会关心你
And the people who truly care about you,
而真正关心你的人
the ones who like you,
喜欢你的人
will always like you,
永远都喜欢你
will always care about you.
关心你
You think these people are insignificant.
你又觉得这部分人啊价值无足轻重
What's this called?
这叫什么
This is being cheap. Just cheap. This person is just that cheap. You always think, what's the point of you liking me? The person I like doesn't like me back. Why should the person you like have to like you? That's the question.
这就是贱啊 就是贱 这人就是这么贱啊 自己总是觉得啊你们喜欢我有什么用啊 我喜欢的人又不喜欢 凭什么你喜欢的人要喜欢你 这就是一个问题
So you need to understand why you shouldn't deceive yourself.
所以你就要明白这个东西为什么不能骗自己呢
If you do deceive yourself,
啊你一旦欺骗了自己
if you manage to fool yourself,
一旦自自己蒙混过关了
you'll mess up your own feedback system.
把你自己的反馈机制搞乱了
When someone criticizes you,
就是别人骂你一句
you just laugh and say thanks.
你嘿嘿嘿谢谢啊
When someone compliments you,
别人这个夸你一句
you ask why they're praising you,
你说你为什么夸我
you know there's an ulterior motive.
你肯定有目的
You want to go to bed?
你想上床啊
That's how it is.
就是这样
So no matter what,
所以无论怎么样
randomly being nice to someone,
随机的对对你好的人
and then turning around to repay their kindness with ingratitude,
恩将仇报
and then being nice to someone who isn't good to you,
然后呢再对对你不好的人啊
offering this gift,
这个礼物奉上
making them wonder what's going on,
让对方觉得嗯这是什么情况啊
and leaving them puzzled and abstracted.
还能这样呢啊让对方搞抽象
I think you're quite unfathomable.
认为你这人深不可测啊
That's when you become invincible.
这时候你就无敌了
So, often we say we deceive ourselves.
所以很多的时候我们说欺骗自己
We are the ones who most deserve to be deceived in this world.
自己是这世界上最该被欺骗的人
Because you're too self-conscious
因为你自我意识过剩啊
Excessive self-consciousness
自我意识过剩
Often, this leads to chronic anxiety.
很多时候就陷入恒常的焦虑
Because you haven't accomplished anything significant.
因为你没有做成什么大的事情
Then you start to feel like... But you can fool yourself, can't you? I'm doing something really big at home right now. I've planted this vegetable. Hey, I'm awesome. I am. Grandpa Yuan Longping appeared to me in a dream. I'm the god of agriculture. A lot of the time, you shouldn't overthink things.
然后你就会觉得什么 但是你可以欺骗自己啊 我现在在家做的好大事情 我把这菜种了 嘿我真棒 我是啊 袁隆平爷爷这个托梦给我 我是这个农业之神 很多的时候你不要去想太多的
I have to be a certain way.
我一定要怎么样
But I'm just fine even if I'm not great.
而是我不怎么样也很好啊
A name that can be named is not a constant name.
名可名非常名
So, many times we say that if you understand more than one language,
所以很多的时候我们说如果你懂两种以上语言
you'll know that 'name can be named' means 'define your name'.
你就知道名可名的意思叫define thy name啊
Define your name.
Define your name
It means you control the variable.
就是你控制了变数啊
You control the direction of the function.
你控制了这个函数的定向的问题
You define the function.
你定义了函数啊
This is commonly said in programming terms.
这是常说的我们编程来讲的话
Let's talk about how to define a function when calling it
定义函数在调用函数怎么样来讲
So you mean to define the name
所以你名可名意思是define the name啊
Define your name
Define your name
Define thy name
define thy name啊
Any of these works
都可以
Regardless of whether you use Old English or not
甭管你用的是古英语还是怎么样
You're essentially giving something power
就是你是在给一些东西赋能
So you just assign it randomly
所以你就瞎他妈付
It's about breaking your own feedback loop
就是给打破自己的反馈机制
Don't reward good and punish evil
不要赏善罚恶
Don't just be nice
不要谁对我好
to those who are nice to you
我就对谁好
and avoid those
谁对我不好
who aren't as kind This is indeed one approach but over time you'll realize that the people you expect to be nice to you might ignore you And the people you least expect, the ones you don't really pay attention to, might treat you very well.
我就跟人不联系 这的确是一种方法 但你时间长了 你就会发现 其实你期望着对你好的人不会理你 而你不期望的不在意的那些人会对你非常好
So this demonstrates a long-standing aspect of human nature.
所以这个就证明人一种很长的这种东西
It's like you like AA, BB, and C.
就是你喜欢AA喜欢BB喜欢C啊
In the end, it might be C who likes you.
轮圈号最后可能C喜欢你
C might like D, but it doesn't really matter.
可能C喜欢D都无所谓
But the constant human pain lies in this very issue.
但是人的恒常的痛苦就在于此
It's the expectation that your efforts must be rewarded.
就是在于你对你的付出一定要有所回报
Why must your efforts be rewarded?
你的付出为什么要有回报呢
And why must the other person feel obligated to return the favor?
对方又为什么一定要回报你呢
If many people have put in effort for him,
对方如果很多人为他付出
why should he feel obligated to return the favor specifically to you?
为什么一定要回报你呢
Moreover, you told me about this mechanism,
而且你告诉我有这么一个机制
For example, everyone who gave me a like
比如说所有给我点赞的人
I can reply with a like at the touch of a button.
我通过一键我就能给别人回复点赞
Isn't that more convenient?
这样不是更好吗
But if you expect me to go through each person's profile one by one,
但是如果你让我一个一个给这些人循环点进去
He gave a like on his friend's post.
他朋友圈点赞
wouldn't that be exhausting?
那不是会很累吗
When a lot of people like my posts on social media
一旦有很多人朋友圈给我点赞的时候
Do I go and like each of their posts in return?
我会一个一个去回赞吗
Not really, I only respond to those who I truly care about
不是我只会对那些真正我特别在意的人
by replying to their messages
回复他们的信息
Or you could give me a like.
或者啊你给我点赞
I feel really happy
我很高兴
and I’ll chat with you for a bit
我跟你聊两句
It’s definitely like that
一定是这样
So people are just fickle
所以人就是贱
People are not equal. People's preferences are also not equal. All these things are unequal. So, most importantly, you need to convince yourself. Why should others be good to me? Can't I be even better to them?
人之间是不对等的 人之间的喜好也是不对等的 这些东西都是不对等的 所以最重要来讲就是你要骗自己啊 为什么别人对我好 我就不能对别人更好
When others are good to me,
别人对我好
Do I have to be good to them in return?
我就一定要对他好
Can't I be a bit less nice to them?
我不能对他坏一点吗
To test his sincerity
啊以此来检测他的真心
Can't I be a little nicer to those who aren't nice to me?
我不能对对我不好的人好一点嘛
People who aren't nice to me expect me to be unkind back
对我不好的人期待着我对她不好
But if I suddenly treat them well
但是我突然对他好
They'll be surprised
人家嗯
Why is this person like this?
这个人为什么这样
This person must really be Kogoro Mouri
这个人看来真的是毛利小五郎
He's not afraid at all
他都不害怕
Kogoro Mouri is indeed not an ordinary person
毛利小五郎果然不是一般人
So often, you need to disrupt others' feedback mechanisms
所以很多的时候要打破别人的反馈机制
You need to break their preconceptions
要打破别人的预判
Many people suddenly get stunned by me
有很多人就突然被我一下懵逼了
It was supposed to be directed at me
本来是骂我的
But then I say, 'Your suggestions are really great'
后来我说你提的意见真好
And I feel that your thoughts align with mine
然后我觉得你跟你想法一样
At this point, the other person exclaims
这时候对方哎呦
This person is really unfathomable
这个人真的深不可测啊
Scary
太可怕了
Often, you might wonder why Liu Bang was able to conquer the empire
很多时候你看刘邦为什么能夺取天下
why Liu Xiu was able to conquer the empire
刘秀为什么能夺取天下
it’s because sometimes they would show great righteousness to those who were clearly their enemies
都是在于有的时候对自己明明是仇人的人
and at other times, they would suddenly bestow heavy rewards on their deeply mysterious subordinates
突然表现的非常仗义
all of this is about being abstract
有的时候呢又对自己的非常那个什么的
as long as you are abstract enough
深不可测的部下突然施以重赏
as long as your actions are sufficiently enigmatic the other party won't be able to judge you and you also need to give yourself this kind of closed space this is why it's for your mental health
一切的一切都是在于搞抽象 只要你足够抽象 只要你的行为足够封闭 对方就没法判断你 而且你也要给自己这种封闭的东西 这是为什么 这是为了自己的精神健康
we Geminis don't get depressed
我们双子座不会抑郁的
because we have two sides to ourselves
因为我们有两个自己
we often talk to ourselves
自己就经常跟自己对话
we won't feel lonely
也不会孤单
and we won't get depressed
也不会抑郁
So often, we don't take ourselves too seriously
所以很多时候我们就不会拿自己特别当回事
Many personalities are like this
很多性格就是这样
The reason his issue gets complicated
他的问题之所以会陷入纠结
can fall into a self-critical cycle of personal growth
会陷入一种自我的成长的批判
Self-deprecation
自我贬低
Excessive self-consciousness
自我意识过剩
An excess of self-consciousness can be a truly terrifying thing.
自我意识过剩是非常可怕的一件事情
It's about your small
就是你的小
My features are too heavy
我的功能太重了
You place too much importance on gains and losses.
你太重视自己的得失
Why do you care about glory and disgrace?
荣辱的东西要什么呀
In the end, we all die anyway.
最后不都得死吗
So why should you particularly care about fame and fortune?
这不是你为什么要特别在意这些功名利禄呢
Even if he gets it, it won’t truly belong to you.
他得到了他又不会真正属于你
It’s like the clothes you’re wearing.
他就像你身上穿这件衣服
After all, you can always take them off, right?
衣服还可以脱呀对吧
When it comes to all these things,
所以所有这些事情来讲
they are all external possessions.
他都是身外物
Money is an external possession
钱财是身外物
Fame is superficial
名声是虚的
Power fades when the person leaves
权利是人走茶凉
All these things
所有这些东西
Although I tell you
虽然我跟你说
When you're young, you should pursue what you want
年轻的时候你该追逐要追逐
They can exchange for many things They can bring you worldly happiness But in reality, they have no real meaning So don't seek positive feedback from others Give it to yourself Don't pursue anyone's praise for you
他能换取了好多东西 能换取你世俗上的快乐 但是实际上它没有意义 所以你不要追求别人的正向反馈 自己给自己啊 不要追求任何人对你的称赞啊
You are much more handsome than Xu Gong
君美甚徐公何及君也
You need to reinforce this psychological suggestion to yourself
你要给自己加强这种心理暗示
You need to love yourself
就是你自己要爱自己
You need to believe you're the best in the world
你自己要觉得自己老子天下第一
I'm the best
我最棒
I am the chosen one
我是天选之子
Even the heavens favor me
老天爷都喜欢我
Who the hell has wronged me
我谁他妈害我
May the heavens strike him with a bolt of lightning
老天爷子天谴拿个雷劈死他
Right on his head
正劈他天灵盖儿
You should think like this
你就要这么想
You must feel that you are Trump
一定要觉得我就是特朗普啊
I am a legend
我就是一个传奇
A person like this is invincible
这样的人是无敌的
You need to know that many entrepreneurs are actually narcissists.
你要知道很多企业家实际都他妈自恋狂啊
Why do narcissistic personality disorders
为什么自恋型人格障碍
and people with NPD
还有NPD这种人
become so strong?
他为什么会变得强
It’s because, apart from themselves,
是因为他除了自我以外
they can’t see anyone else.
他看不见任何人
So, why is your self-esteem often weak?
所以很多的时候你们的自我为什么弱呢
It’s because your parents in your early family life
就是因为你的父母在原生家庭早期的时候了
subjected you to various forms of psychological abuse.
这是对你更更种变变态的打击
Making you feel like you have no self-worth
让你觉得自身没有价值感
So then Why do you pursue a sense of self-worth? It’s because you just want to gain your parents' love But your parents are really terrible people So don’t try to get it from your parents Instead, get it from your cyber godfathers online
然后呢 你为什么要追求自身的价值感呢 是因为你其实就是想获得爸爸妈妈的爱而已 但你爸妈是很操蛋的人 所以你就不要从自己爸妈那儿获得 就从网络赛博义父这儿获得
Not just from me, but from others as well
不光从我这儿获得自己
How could this even happen, right?
怎么还他妈能生成对吧
We should do it ourselves
自己就咱自己动手
to be self-sufficient
丰衣足食
Why would I want praise from my enemy?
我为什么要得到来自敌人的称赞呢
An enemy wouldn’t praise me anyway
敌人他也不会称赞我
Even if an enemy did praise me
敌人就算称赞我
they would still try to eliminate me with an attack
他也会用进攻方式来消灭我
They might praise me after they’ve eliminated me
消灭完了我他可能会对我称赞
because the enemy and I are in conflict
因为我跟敌人是敌我矛盾
Your relationship with some people’s parents is also a conflict
你跟有些人的父母之间就是敌我矛盾
The relationship between you and the person you're pursuing is also a conflict of interests.
你跟你追求的人之间也是敌我矛盾
He might have many admirers.
他有可能有很多追求者
Your parents may just want to send you off sooner.
你的父母可能就是想把你早点送出去
He feels that you're causing trouble in his life.
他觉得你给他生活添麻烦
In reality, you're a burden.
实际是个累赘
He should have loved you.
他本来应该爱你
but hasn't given you enough attention
却给没有给你足够多的关注
Enough reciprocation.
足够多的回馈
Enough contribution.
足够多的贡献
Not giving you enough love
没有给你足够多的爱
That's because he's a jerk
那是因为他操蛋
There's a conflict between you two
你们之间就是敌我矛盾
A conflict
敌我矛盾
Why do you insist on getting an award from your enemy?
为什么你非要让敌人给你发奖状呢
So isn't the issue with you?
所以那不是你自己有问题吗
So your approach is flawed
所以你的方式就有问题
You should love yourself
你应该自己爱自己
The essence of loving yourself is about fooling yourself It's about deceiving yourself But then, what is reality? Aren't you the most adorable person? Aren't you the most important person in this universe? Because you are the most important in your universe.
自己爱自己的核心就是欺骗自己 就是欺骗自己 而但是什么又是真实呢 难道你不是一个最可爱的人吗 难道你不是这个宇宙中最重要的人吗 因为你在你的宇宙里最重要啊
Your universe begins with you.
你的宇宙以你开始
And ends with you.
以你结束
After you pass away,
你死亡了以后之后
how others criticize you
别人怎么骂你
You can't hear anymore either.
你也听不见了呀
You don't know how your loved ones are doing.
你的这些亲人过得好不好
You don't know anymore.
你也不知道了呀
So your life is over.
所以你的生命都结束了
Why do you care about those deep comments?
你在意那些深厚评干什么呢
Right, so it's meaningless.
对所以没有意义
So you should make your life the top priority.
所以你要以活着的自己为最高目标
Don't chase after others' likes
不要去追求别人的点赞
Don't seek others' follow-backs.
不要去追求别人的回粉
Don’t go chasing after other people’s approval
不要去追求别人的青睐
There’s no smoke without fire
无事不登三宝殿
He’s always looking for you
他他妈天天找着你
It can’t be anything good
肯定没好事
It’s either mischief or theft
非奸即盗
Isn’t he just after the old lady’s money?
不就是惦记老妇的屁股眼子呢
Right?
是不是
So in many cases, it’s bound to be nothing good
所以很多的时候来讲肯定没有好事
Or else he wants to borrow money from you
要不就跟你借钱
Or I'll mess with you
要不就搞你
Or I'll mess with you and take your money too
要不就是又搞你又要走你钱
So it's always like this
所以都是这样
Isn't it all about mutual deception between men and women
男女之间的事不就是互相欺骗
Satisfying our own hormonal sexual desires
满足自己的荷尔蒙的这些性欲这些事吗
So in the end, what's all this talk about love
所以到头来最后又说爱情又说什么
It ends up being a mess
结果弄得啊
With child support and all sorts of issues
孩子抚养费乱七八糟
Divorces, remarriages, and everything else
又离婚又结婚什么
These things are just repetitive.
这些事其实翻来覆去
You realize they're all the same.
你发现就是一样
So you have to deceive yourself. My goddess they're just too shy to tell me. He actually loves me. You know? So you have to deceive yourself. You need to deceive yourself. I'm the most useful person in this world.
所以你要欺骗自己 我的女神啊 那都是不好意思跟我说 他其实就是爱我 知道吗 所以你要欺骗自己 你要欺骗自己 我是这世界上最有用的人
I can succeed wherever I go.
我到哪儿我都能成功啊
Problems get solved wherever I am.
我到哪儿这问题就解决了
But you can fool yourself.
但你可以欺骗自己
Aside from not stepping into minefields.
除了不要去雷区踩地雷以外
You can do anything you want.
你做任何事情都是可以的
You give yourself a hundred percent confidence.
你自己给了自己百分之百的肯定
You constantly cheer yourself on and boost your morale.
你自己不断的给加油打气
Just like when you play Gundam games.
就像你玩高达游戏
Playing anything
玩任何东西
Others cheer you on
那别人给你加油打气
You always rely on
你老靠
I'll cheer you on
我给你加油打气
I'm the healer
我是牧师
I'm the support
我是辅助
If you can heal yourself
你自己要是能回血
Wouldn't that be awesome
那不就厉害了吗
If a character can take down others
你一个角色如果他又能干掉别人
You can heal yourself
自己还能回血
Isn't that awesome?
那不就厉害吗
So the most important thing is to heal yourself
所以最重要的就是自己给自己回血
Healing yourself
自己给自己回血
Are you really going to push it that far?
难道你非要做成了啊
Climbed Mount Tai
上了泰山
Visited the Great Wall
上了长城
You climbed the steps
你登了攀了级
And then you went skydiving
然后那个跳了伞
Then I went paragliding
然后做了滑翔伞
Then that person landed on the moon
然后那个登了月
Are you the one who has value?
你才是有价值的人吗
No, not at all
不是啊
I was born feeling that I am a valuable person
我天生我就觉得我是有价值的人
And I further through
而且我再通过
Later, whether it was a small achievement or a big one
后来无论是小的成就还是大成就
I would reinforce this impression But no matter how the world responds to me I always love myself No matter how dark this society may be to me No matter how many blows I know I am a person of value I am destined to achieve something great in this life
我都会加深这种印象 但无论这世界对我怎么反馈 我始终爱我自己 无论这社会对我如果有多黑暗 多少打击 我都知道我是有价值的人 我都注定知道我这辈子一定会干成伟大的事
Even if I don’t accomplish great things
就算不干成伟大事
I’ll come back in the next life
我下辈子再来
It’s okay
没关系
Let’s just enjoy this life
这辈子咱就享福
Let's just take a cursory look
咱就走马观花
Let's just demo it
咱就demo
So what if it's just a preview version
咱就预先体验版又怎么了
Right?
对不对
So you need to break this cycle in your mind
所以你就要打破自己内心这种循环机制啊
You need to set high goals for yourself
你要知道你给自己设定高目标
It's not about how strict you are with yourself
不是你给自己的要求有多强
It's because you haven't received enough love
而是你得到的爱太少
You haven't received enough love
你得到的爱太少
So you always try to achieve high-value goals
所以你老想通过完成高价值的目标
to earn your parents' love
来实现父母对你的爱
but your parents are just terrible
但是你的父母他妈操蛋
they won’t give it to you
他不会给你的
they treat you like they’re training a dog
他像训狗一样对你嗯
you’re just a dog in the Panhong Park
你就是潘虹园区里的一条狗
so how could you be happy
所以你怎么会开心呢
right
对不对
his goal is to domesticate you
他的目的是驯化你
Don't let him harm you
不要让他对你
or harm himself
他自己有害
You don't harm your parents
你不害你的父母
This is the best application of filial piety
这就是孝道的最好的用处的地方
But if your parents harm you
但是你的父母害你
You have no way out If your parents bully you Is that called bullying That's called normal education This is normal. That's the most terrifying aspect of filial piety culture. It's one-sided suffering. There's no way to control it. You haven't seen in mental hospitals,
你没招你没招 父母那欺负你 那叫欺负吗 那叫正常教育 您这是正常 所以这就是孝道文化最可怕的地方 就是单方面受害 没有办法控 你在精神病院没看见
parents driven mad by their children.
说北被他妈孩子逼疯的父母
You only see children driven mad by their parents.
你只看见被父母逼疯的孩子啊
I just watched all the UPloaders who passed away in 2024.
我刚看了2024年所有在逝世的up主
Most of them couldn't see a way out.
大部分人都是想不开啊
If we can't figure it out, let's break this mechanism.
想不开咱们就打破这种机制
If we can't figure it out, let's switch to a new method for our operating system.
想不开咱就给自己的操作系统换一套方法
Let's change our mindset.
换一套想法
This intense hope is the path to artificial life.
就这样高强度的期盼自己是通向人工人啊
Artificial life and happiness.
人工人生幸福的啊
It's a necessary journey.
必经之路
Trust me.
相信我啊
No matter what.
无论怎么样
People are at their lowest when they have no dignity.
人至贱啊
People become invincible when they have no shame.
人不要脸
Unstoppable in the world.
天下无敌
What is dignity?
什么是脸呢
What is truth?
什么又是真呢
The world is all illusions.
世间都是虚妄
What is real?
什么又是真的
You deceive yourself.
你骗自己
Aren't you really very cute?
难道你自己不是真的很可爱
You are very cute.
你就是很可爱
You are amazing.
你就是很棒啊
So don't worry about all that nonsense.
所以不用去想那些乱七八糟的
I say you're great.
我说你棒
You are great.
你就是棒
When I say you're great.
说你棒
Even if you're not, you are.
不棒也棒
But why do you give me this power?
但你为什么要给我这种权利呢
Why do you give me the right to name you? You need to define yourself. To surprise everyone. The most important thing is to define. It's not about the fees you display. It's not about the reputation you show.
为什么要给我名可名名你名的权利呢 你要明自己啊 一鸣惊人 最重要的就是define 你自己不是在于你显示上面的费用啊 不是在于你显示了什么声望
It's not about the achievements you make.
不是在于你做了什么achievement
It's about loving yourself naturally.
而是在于你自己天生就爱自己
Heaven brought me into this world.
老天爷把我生在这世界上
God must really love me
老天爷就是爱我的
Right?
对不对
So you are a part of Heaven.
所以你是老天爷的一部分
So names that can be named are not true names.
所以名可名非常名
The way that can be spoken is not the true way.
道可道非常道
You need to define your own life.
你要自己去定义你自己的人生
I am already complete today.
我今天本已具足啊
How can there be any debt?
何来的亏欠
I am already in a state of perfect completeness.
我本来我就是天下非常圆满的一个状态
Why should I seek perfection?
我何来修行啊
I am already in a perfect state.
所以我本身我就是一个完美状态啊
I am Maitreya Buddha in the world.
我就是弥勒佛在世
I am the future.
我就是未来
The future again.
又是未来
The present as well.
又是现代啊
Having seen the future, why should I fail?
既见未来为何不败
That's how it is.
就是这样
So our future will definitely lead to completeness.
所以我们未来一定会通向圆满
Why should we care about imperfections in the process?
所以我们要为什么要在意我
Why should we worry about anything less than perfect?
过程之间有什么不完美之类的事情呢
So love yourself.
所以爱自己
Starting today.
从今天开始